

Mr. Hemant Singhi

First name: Hemant Nationality: Indian

Last name:SinghiAddress:Room 213A, 1/F House 2, 302Date of birth:06/08/1994Wan's Lodge, Tai Po Tsai

Web: http://ww.hemantsinghi.com Village, Clearwaterbay Road, Kowloon, Hong Kong

Phone number: +852-67634128

Email address: hssinghi@connect.ust.hk

1 Profile

I am pursuing Master of Science in Information Technology from the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong, I have undertaken several certifications and training from leading organizations such as RedHat, VMware and Microsoft. I am a certified Linux System Admin and Windows Server Admin and also have exposures to technology like Virtualization and also on different programming languages. I have also worked as "Web Developer Intern" at Zenitex Pvt. Ltd and Mera Medicare LLP. I have also been an key organizer at AURO University, Surat for various events while pursuing my Bachelor's degree. New challenges and tasks ignites a motivational spark inside me.



Work experience

01/2015 - 07/2015

Web developer Intern

Mera Medicare LLP, New Delhi, India

This was an virtual internship. I have contributed in variety of areas such as Web Development and Designing, Quality Analysis, De-Bugging, Digital marketing etc. Some of my major achievements are:

- 1. Comprehensive quality analysis of the system
- 2. Added features and functions whenever needed
- 3. Gathered database of medicines from various sources
- 4. Designing and development of the website on live server

05/2014 - 08/2015

Web developer Intern

Zenitex Pvt. Ltd, Surat, India

- 1. Create a personal website of Mr. Viral Desai, CEO which has following features:
 - 1. cross browser and cross device compatible website,
 - 2. Open Graph tools,
 - 3. Google Analytics tool.

02/2016 - present

Web Developer

The BASE, Hong Kong

Responsible for developing, designing and maintaining their website.

URL: http://base.ust.hk



Work experience

02/2016 - present

Web developer

hackUST 2016, Hong Kong

Develop the phase 1 website for the Hackathon at Hong Kong University of Science and Technology.

URL: http://www.hack.ust.hk

http://frosil.website/hackUST/HackUST2

Projects

01/2012 - 04/2012

HTML, JS, CSS

Revenge Monsters, Surat, India

A dynamic website created with features like JavaScript, HTML, CSS and Servlets. In the website

there are forms in which user inputs are stored in a database and automated mail is generated and sent to the user

09/2012 - 12/2012

C++

Telephone Billing System, Surat, India

A C++ project developed to generate bill for the customer whose phone number is entered. User can add/delete/modify customer records and generate the bill.

08/2013 - 12/2013

VB .net

Inventory Management System, Surat, India

Project developed in VB .net for managing the Inventory of IT department of a company.

01/2014 - 04/2014

Android

Converter, Surat, India

Android application used to convert Numbers, Data storage, Currency and Force units.

09/2015 - 12/2015

Android + Web Technologies

Class Reminder, Hong Kong

Class Reminder as the name suggests it will remind the students about their classes. Whenever a student registers himself on the app automatic reminders are created for the student, that will remind students about the class 1 hour before.



Education

04/2009 - 04/2010

Senior Secondary (X)

S.D. Jain Modern School, Surat, India

I have obtained CGPA 8.4 in CBSE board exam.

04/2011 - 03/2012

Commerce

S.D. Jain Modern School, Surat, India

I have obtained a percentage of 83% in CBSE board exam.

Education

04/2012 - 07/2012

System Administration

Rooman Technologies, Bengaluru, India

I have successfully completed following topics with Grade A.

- 1. A+ Core (DIH)
- 2. Network (N+)
- 3. 70-642 TS: Windows Server 2008
- 4. Network Infrastructure, Configuring
- 5. 70-680 TS: Windows 7,
- 6. Configuring
- 7. CCNA TCP/IP & IP Addressing
- 8. Linux System Admin

08/2012 - 07/2015

B.Sc. in Information Technology

AURO University, Surat, India

I have obtained a CGPA of 3.41 out of 4.0 scale. I was also awarded with a Silver medal for securing the Second position.

Following courses were covered:

- 1. PYTHON
- 2. ASP.Net MVC
- 3. LINUX and Shell Programming
- 4. Web Technologies
- 5. Design and Analysis of Algorithms
- 6. Programming in JAVA
- 7. Advanced Networks
- 8. Advanced Web Programming
- 9. Data Structure using C
- 10. Introduction to Digital Electronics

09/2015 - present

M.Sc. in Information Technology

Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong

I have obtained a CGPA of 3.0.

Following courses were covered:

- 1. Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery
- 2. Computer Networks: An Internet Perspective
- 3. Digital Forensic and Legal Issues
- 4. Android



Coding Languages

PHP Professional English Full
HTML Professional Hindi Native

CSS Professional Gujarati Professional JavaScript Limited Cantonese Learning

MySQL Limited
C Limited
C++ Limited

Java Professional
Android Development Professional
node js Elementary